我叫巴里·艾伦
My name is Barry Allen,
是现今世上速度最快的人
and I am the fastest man alive.
在外人看来
To the outside world,
我只是个普通的鉴证专员
I'm an ordinary forensic scientist,
但在尖端科研实验室的朋友们的帮助下
but secretly, with the help of my friends at S.T.A.R. Labs,
我秘密地打击犯罪  寻找跟我一样的超能力者
I fight crime and find other meta-humans like me.
我让杀害母亲的凶手自食其果
I hunted down the man who killed my mother,
但我们的世界也因此出现了新的威胁
but in doing so, I opened up our world to new threats.
我是唯一来得及阻止他们的人
And I am the only one fast enough to stop them.
我是闪电侠
I am the Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on "The Flash"...
你就这么让我们走吗
You're just letting us go?
只需记住是谁保护你们
Just remember who it was made sure
没被扔上那架飞机就行
you didn't get thrown on that plane.
我称之为天气魔棒
I call it the Wizard's Wand.
辛格队长说你的反超能力者特别行动小组
Captain Singh mentioned there may be positions available
可能还要人
on your anti-meta-human task force.
-为什么要加入  -马克·马登杀了我爸爸
- Why do you want to do this? - Mark Mardon killed my dad.
我是詹姆斯·杰西  大人  外号
James Jesse, your honor, aka...
魔术师
The Trickster.
反正你也要进监狱了  詹姆斯
You're going to prison either way, James.
离我远点  离我父亲远点
You stay away from me and you stay away from my father.
如果他发现自己也许有个儿子
If he finds out that he might have a son
在不知道他的情况下长大
that grew up without knowing him,
会击垮他的
it would crush him.
杰西是我的女儿  极速抓走了她
Jesse's my daughter and Zoom has her.
接下来就该你了
You're next.
尖端科研实验室
动手啊  杀了我
Go ahead. Kill me.
但是...我女儿...
But...my daughter...
是无辜的
is innocent.
求你...
Please...
把
let
杰西...
Jesse...
放了..
live...
快点啊
Go on.
说句话吧
Say something!
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
为了买最后一个  我和一个老太太掐起来了
I had to fight some old lady for the last one.
那里没有绿箭侠人偶卖
They didn't have any Green Arrow dolls.
都不知道你为什么要买那个疯子的人偶
Don't know why you'd want a toy of that crazy man.
我想不出要送巴里什么
I can't figure out what to get Barry.
我觉得你可以送他这个
I was thinking you could give him this.
是挺不错
Oh, that's nice.
但我想送个更有意义的东西
But I kind of want to get him something more meaningful.
我是说  最近一年又奇怪又伤感
I mean, it's been a strange, emotional 12 months.
谁说不是呢
Yeah, you don't have to tell me.
我明白的  宝贝  我也很想念艾迪
Oh, I know, babe. I miss Eddie too.
要不你送巴里一块好点的手表吧
How about you get Barry a really nice watch?
就像本爷爷送你的那块
Like grandpa Ben gave to you.
这主意不错
That ain't a bad idea.
我爸给送我这块表是因为我总迟到
You know, my dad only gave me this watch because I was always late.
-是吗  -是啊
- You? - Yeah.
他挑的礼物都带有明确的暗示
He always gave a gift with a not-so-hidden message,
比如这块表  还有一次他送我拉力器
like this watch or the time he bought me free weights
因为他嫌我太瘦
because he said I was too skinny.
我跟他说  "我以后要是有了儿子
I told him, "When I have a son,
我只会送他有趣的礼物"
I'm only giving him fun presents."
这玩意儿都不准了  但我不知为何还戴着它
This thing barely works. Don't know why I still wear it.
因为是家人送的
Because it's from family.
你真的没事吗
You sure you're all right?
没事  真的
Yeah, yeah. I promise.
我们应该更专业点
You know, we should really be more professional.
你知道是你先挑起的吧
You do realize you initiated that.
知道  我准备好谴责我自己了
Yes, and I'm fully prepared to reprimand myself then.
我是说  任何人都可能会进来
I'm just saying, you know, anyone could walk in,
比如乔  还有队长...
like, Joe or captain...
但是我四点到十二点还要...
But I have, like, a 4:00 to 12:00, but...
-回见  -好的
- I'll see you later. - Yeah, all right.
-圣诞节见  -行  回见
- I'll see you for Christmas. - Yeah, okay. Bye.
我真为你高兴  真的
I'm so happy for you. Truly.
谢谢
Thank you.
你喜欢她  对我很重要
It means a lot to me that you like her.
我不知道
I don't know.
威尔斯  给我留言说
Wells, um, he left me that message where he said
我不会真正的快乐
that I'd never really be happy.
有阵子  我真的开始相信他的话
And for a while I really started to believe him,
但现在  我也不知道  或许能
but, now...I-- I don't know. Maybe there is a way to--
你还好吗  怎么了
Are you okay? What's wrong?
真抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我守不住这个秘密了  巴里
I can't keep this in anymore, Barry.
什么秘密
What?
我知道自己以前很生你和爸爸的气
I know I was so mad at you and dad
因为你们不告诉我你就是闪电侠
for not telling me that you were the Flash,
但现在我知道了一件事
but when I found out about this,
我却不知该怎么办
I didn't know what to do.
什么事  发生什么事了
What? What's going on?
弗朗辛回来的时候  爸爸叫我别信她
When Francine came back, my dad told me not to trust her
他是对的
and he was right.
我不太了解
I didn't know how much.
妈妈离开我们的时候
When my mother left us,
怀着身孕
she was pregnant.
她有个儿子
She had a son.
乔的儿子  我的弟弟
Joe's son. My brother.
他叫什么
What's his name?
沃利
Wally.
沃利·韦斯特
Wally West.
我知道了以后  我让她赶紧离开
When I found out, I told her to leave
而且永远别回来  也别告诉我老爸
and never come back and to never tell my dad,
可是  巴里  我觉得
but Barry, I feel--
这件事把我整个人都掏空了
I feel like this is hollowing me out.
每次我面对老爸的时候
Every time I look at dad,
我都觉着自己是在伤害他
I feel like I'm hurting him.
我不  我不知道该怎么做
I don't-- I don't know what to do.
我觉得你知道自己该怎么做
I think you know what you have to do.
我不能  那样他会伤心死的
I can't. It's gonna kill him.
不  不过会的
No, it won't.
你不用一个人去说  我会陪着你的
You don't have to do this alone. We can tell him together.
谢谢
Thank you.
没关系
Yeah.
快看  下雪了
Hey, look. Snow.
或许今年会是个银装素裹的圣诞节
Maybe it'll be a white Christmas.
那就太好了
That'd be nice.
我之前一直在想  如果我们能
I was thinking that if we could inject
把不稳定的中微子注射到各个缺口中
an unstable neutrino burst into the individual breaches,
它们或许就能自己封闭起来了
it might cause them to seal on their own.
这样就能阻止极速在我们两个世界来回穿梭了
And stop Zoom from travelling back and forth between our worlds.
至少我们不用再担心他会派
At least then we wouldn't have to worry about him
超能力者来杀巴里了
sending any more meta-humans over for Barry to fight.
-这意义很大  -什么意思
- It means a lot. - What does?
你关心着巴里
You looking after Barry.
最近这几周他经历了很多事
He's been through a lot the last few weeks.
我并不只是想保证巴里的安全
Barry's not the only person here I want to keep safe.
天呐  赶紧亲嘴吧
Oh, dear Lord, just kiss already.
-太饥渴了  -一切都好吗
- Oh, the thirst is real. - Is everything all right?
是的  我一直在看着
Yeah, I keep checking,
超能力者方面没有任何情况
but all is quiet on the meta-human front.
你觉得极速是去过圣诞节了吗
Hey, you think Zoom decided to take Christmas off?
什么是圣诞节
What's Christmas?
在这个节日期间
Oh, well, it's this holiday we have
我们会砍砍树  唱唱歌
where we cut down trees and sing songs
来庆祝两千多年前一个小孩的诞生
to celebrate the birth of a baby 2,000 years ago,
后来  他被罗马人杀了
and then the Romans killed him
所以我们彼此要互赠礼物
so we give each other gifts--
你就这么给人家解释吗
That's your explanation?
-我知道什么是圣诞节  -当然
- I know what Christmas is. - Oh, right, of course.
乔  巴里还有爱瑞丝
You know, Joe and Barry and Iris
邀请大家去他们那过平安夜
are having people over for Christmas Eve,
而且他们说我们邀请谁去都可以
and they said we could invite whoever we want.
-你  你想要邀请谁去  -你
- Who-- who do you want? - You.
我是说我想邀请你去
I want to invite you, I mean.
看你们俩说话太痛苦了  你们看见哈里了吗
This is so painful. Have you guys seen Harry?
没有  我交代他要多休息
No, I have not. I told him to rest.
他和我的其他男性病人一样固执
He's just as stubborn as all the rest of my male patients in this place.
我还是不打扰你们了  好吧
I'm gonna leave you two alone, okay?
我去找哈里了
I'm gonna go find Harry.
天呐
Holy Hannah!
-一切都好吧  -当然
- Everything okay? - Sure.
为什么会不好呢
Why wouldn't it be?
铁山监狱
这雪下得真大
Man, it's really coming down.
新闻里没说要下雪
The news didn't say anything about snow.
可能这是圣诞节的奇迹
Maybe it's a Christmas miracle.
让它下吧
Let it snow.
我们有情况...
We got a code...
咚咚咚
Knock, knock.
这个
So.
提前假释  你有兴趣吗
Early parole. You interested?
我不想多嘴  可是出口是在上面
Don't mean to be a noodge, but the exit is upstairs.
还需要一样东西
Just need one more thing.
最高安全级别牢房
你跟我开玩笑吧
You got to be kidding me.
这才像个圣诞节
It's beginning to look a lot like Christmas.
这不是真的吧
Please tell me this is not happening...
是真的  圣诞老人不喜欢我们了
It's official, Santa hates us.
这场突如其来的暴风雪把摄像头
This sudden blizzard took out cameras
还有安保系统都破坏了
and the security system.
谢天谢地没死人
I mean, thank God nobody was killed,
但是找不到马登  杰西和史纳特的踪迹
but there's no trace of Mardon, Jesse, or Snart.
说到这个  马登又出现了
Speaking of which, with Mardon back on the scene...
帕蒂可能会不太理智
Patty might not be thinking so clearly.
什么意思  马登跟帕蒂有什么关系
What do you mean? What does Mardon have to do with Patty?
我们应该预料到
We should have expected this.
气压能降得这么低意味着马登回来了
The unexpected drop in barometric pressure had to mean Mardon was back in town.
帕蒂
Patty...
杰西无法跟外界有任何交流
Jesse was on full communication lock down,
可这并不意味着马登和史纳特没有联系
But that doesn't mean Mardon and Snart weren't in contact.
帕蒂  乔跟我说了马登的事
Patty, Joe told me about Mardon.
我现在不能跟你谈这个
I can't talk to you about this.
帕蒂  没关系的
Hey, Patty, it's okay.
我去跟她谈
Got it.
巴里  你是个好人
Look, Barry, you're a sweet guy,
可是你不知道这座城市面临什么危险
but you have no idea what's really going on in this city.
你甚至都不知道哈里森·威尔斯...
I mean, you don't even know that Harrison Wells...
对不起  我没时间跟你说所有的事
I'm sorry, I don't have time to bring you up to speed.
真讽刺
That's ironic.
帕蒂  我很关心你
Patty, look. I care about you a lot.
我不想让你做任何鲁莽的事
I don't want to see you do anything reckless.
我是警察
I'm a cop.
追捕罪犯是我的职责
Going after criminals is in my job description.
不是鲁莽
It's not reckless.
不管有没有超能力  马登都要为所做的事负责
And powers or not, Mardon's gonna answer for what he's done.
帕蒂
Patty...
*用名叫霍莉的*
*Deck the halls*
*女孩的残肢来装饰墙壁*
*With body parts from a girl named Holly*
这好像不是歌词吧
I don't remember those being the lyrics.
我是极具创作天赋的  这毋庸置疑
I am tremendously creative. That I can tell you.
最好是这样  我把你放出来不是...
You'd better be. I didn't break you out--
我把你们放出来
I didn't break either of you out,
不是为了交新朋友的
because I was looking to make some new friends.
那可不太符合节日气氛  大明星
That is not the holiday spirit, marky-mark.
圣诞节是个团聚的日子
Christmas is a time for togetherness.
还有什么比万人塚更能表现团聚精神的呢
And what says togetherness more than mass graves?
你为什么放我们出来呢
So why did you break us out?
我欠你个人情
Well, I owed you one,
至于他嘛  他就是个疯子
and this guy, he's just crazy.
这算恭维了
It's a compliment.
而且我们都有着共同的目的
And we all want the same thing.
-时尚建议吗  -希望闪电侠死
- Fashion advice? - To see The Flash dead.
那可算得上是新年愿望了
Well, that was more of a new years resolution,
不过我无所谓的
but, hey, I'm flexible.
这屋里的人都试过了  结果不怎么样
That hasn't gone so well for anyone in this room.
什么让你认为这次就能打败他呢
What makes you think you can stop him this time?
以三敌一
Three against one.
而且  他现在已经大不如前了
Plus, the one isn't quite what he was.
另一个穿黑衣的极速者
See, another speedster dressed all in black
几周前差点把他干掉了
nearly took him out a few weeks ago.
他很脆弱  容易受伤
He's vulnerable. He's weak.
低估他是错误的
It's a mistake to underestimate him.
用我的超能力  加上他的天资
With my power, his... flair,
还有你的聪明才智
and your smarts,
我们可以一举铲除他
we can put him in the ground for good.
-说说你的计划  -先告诉我你是否加入
- Tell me your plan. - Tell me you're in.
-我在考虑  -还有什么问题
- I'm thinking about it. - What's the matter?
坐了几个月牢就让你变得软弱了吗  史纳特
A few months in the clink make you soft, did it, Snart?
-你想跳舞吗  -小子们
- You wanna dance? - Boys, boys, boys!
友善一点  放轻松  马登
Play nice! Mellow out, Mardon.
别生气  史纳特  我有个主意
Don't have a snit, Snart. Here's an idea.
我们出去喝几杯  干掉几个唱颂歌的
We all go out, have a few drinks, kill some carolers.
然后就都舒服了
We'll all feel better.
好吧
All right.
你觉得怎么样  史纳特
So what's it gonna be, Snart?
好极了
Oh, yeah.
天气巫师  寒冷队长  还有魔术师
The Weather Wizard, Captain Cold, and the Trickster.
他们三个打你一个  我觉得胜算很小
There's three of them and one of you. I do not like those odds.
而且我没有速度就根本帮不上忙  所以...
And I'm gonna be no help without my speed, so...
我头顶上有个灯泡  我有主意了
Oh, oh, light bulb up here. I have an idea.
大部分天气现象都有迹可循  没别的意思
Most weather phenomena are marked, no pun intended,
都是由大气的电荷和电压的改变而形成的
by the change of electric charge and pressure in the atmosphere.
我们可以在地图上标记出那些波动
We could just map out those fluctuations--
来确定他的位置
To pinpoint his location.
没错  那就只需要移除所有
Right, it would just be a matter of removing all--
围绕在他周围的电量
The electricity from his immediate surroundings.
把他引到一个地方
Attracting it to one spot.
就像避雷针一样
The same way a lightning rod does.
只不过不是避雷针  我们用...
Only instead of a lightning rod, we could use...
魔棒
A wand?
这段对话是不是已经说过了
Have we already had this conversation?
-差不多吧  -什么意思
- Kind of. - What does that mean?
是这样  马登上一次来袭
All right, so the last time Mardon attacked,
他制造了一起海啸  摧毁了整个中城
he, um, generated a tidal wave that destroyed all of Central City.
那你们现在为什么还活得好好的呢
So why are you not all sleeping with the fishes?
地球二有《教父》吗
Earth-2 has "The Godfather"?
每个地球都有《教父》  维托[《教父》中人物]
Every earth has "The Godfather," Vito.
所以我穿越时空
So I ran back through time.
回到了前一天  让一切重演
One day into the past and I got a do-over
在他伤害别人前阻止了他
and I stopped Mardon before he could hurt anyone.
你不该干扰时间线的
You shouldn't have messed with the timeline.
另一个威尔斯也是这样说的
That's what the other Wells said.
所以好消息是  在那条时间线上
So the good news is, in that timeline,
你造出了魔棒  而且成功了
you created the wand and it worked.
所以你只需再做一次
So you just got to do it again.
第一次再做一次
For the first time.
-是啊  压力真不大  -我可以帮你
- Yeah, no pressure. - I can give you a hand.
-两个世界里的尖子联手  -我喜欢
- Best of both worlds? - I like that.
你没事吧  哈里
You good, Harry?
没事  有什么可不好的呢
Yeah, why wouldn't I be?
节日忧郁症吗
Holiday blues?
他女儿还在极速手上一定让他很不好过
It can't be easy knowing Zoom still has his daughter.
是啊  我一会就回来
Yeah, all right, look, I'll be right back.
我有点事情要去处理
I have something I have to deal with.
好吧  上一次你俩这样看着我时
Okay, the last time the two of you were looking at me like that,
是你俩开着我的敞篷车出去兜风
it was when you both took my convertible on a joy ride and wrapped it around
然后还撞上了那棵大橡树
that big oak tree on Fairmont drive.
爸爸
Dad...
是这样  乔  我们有话要对你说
All right, Joe, we have something we need to tell you.
不
No...
是我有话要对你说
I have something that I need to tell you.
关于弗朗辛的
It's about Francine.
她离开我们的时候...
When she left us...
怀有身孕
she was pregnant.
那孩子生下来了吗
Did she have the baby?
是的
Yes.
他的名字叫沃利
His name is Wally.
沃利·韦斯特
Wally West.
华莱士的简称
Short for Wallace.
假如你是个男孩  我们就会给你起这名字
That's what we were gonna name you if you were a boy.
我也是几周前才知道这事的
I only found out a couple weeks ago.
爸爸  我很抱歉没早点告诉你
Dad, I am so sorry that I didn't tell you sooner.
这么多年过去了  她就是因为这事找到我们
That's why she reached out to us after all these years.
她想让我们知道  在...
She wanted us to know before... she...
在她去世前
Before she died.
我还以为弗朗辛不会再给我弄出什么意外了
And I thought Francine was running out of surprises.
我得回去工作了
I got to get to work.
爸爸  听我说  爸爸
Dad, listen-- dad.
对不起
I'm-- I'm sorry.
让我先平复一下
Just let me sit with it.
你觉得他不会有事吧
Do you think that he's gonna be okay?
不会的  我觉得
I do, yeah, I think--
只是一时难以接受
It's just a lot to take in.
他需要点时间来接受这个事实
He just needs a little time to process it.
不配点小棉花糖  可可都没啥味道
Cocoa isn't cocoa without the mini marshmallows.
你没在家  我检查过了
And you're out. I checked.
你疯了吗
Are you out of your mind?
敢闯进我家里来
Breaking into my home?
小心点  我给冷冻枪做了点小改动
Careful. I made an upgrade to the cold gun.
要是我松开枪柄
If I release my grip from the handle,
内核就会达到临界状态
the core goes critical.
你也许能躲过一劫
You might make it,
她就难说了
She won't.
我读了你那篇关于消失的中产阶级的文章了
Read your article on the disappearing middle class.
观点明确  行文流畅
Strong point of view. Nice prose style.
谢谢  能得到杀人狂的青睐
Yeah, well, who needs a Pulitzer
谁还需要普利策奖呢
when you have a homicidal maniac's seal of approval.
巴里没告诉过你吗  我有个十分艰辛的童年
Didn't Barry tell you? I had a rough childhood.
这屋子里谁的童年都没好到哪儿去
Everyone in this room had a rough childhood.
-忍着点吧  -你来这什么事  史纳特
- Get over it. - Why are you here, Snart?
圣诞节要到了  我想送你份礼物
I got the Noel spirit, wanted to give you a gift.
马登把杰西和我放出来杀死你
Mardon broke Jesse and me out to kill you.
杰西肯定是同意了  高兴地手舞足蹈
Jesse's on board, of course. He's shaking with excitement.
至于我  还是算了吧
Me, I'm gonna pass.
为什么  你长良心了
Why? You grow a conscience?
马登想要复仇  杰西想制造混乱
Mardon wants revenge. Jesse wants chaos.
这俩样我都不怎么感兴趣
I'm just not invested like they are.
你想说的是干这事捞不到钱吧
You mean there's no money in it for you?
我对无偿劳动一直都不怎么感冒
I was never much for non-profit work.
既然你跟他们不是一伙的
If you're not in with them,
那就告诉我他们在哪
then tell me where they are.
不  就把我想像成一个神秘圣诞老人吧
Nah, consider me more of a secret Santa.
并且  你那帮朋友都很热衷解密
Besides, you and your friends love to solve a good mystery.
别胡扯了  史纳特
You are full of it, Snart.
我觉得我和朋友们救了你妹妹
I think my friends and I saved your sister's life,
你受不了欠着我的人情
and you can't stand owing me a marker.
我本来不想告诉你
I hate to break it to you,
但你刚才的那种行为叫做讲信用
but that-- that right there is called honor.
继续  把话说完  我能看出你迫不及待
Go on, make your pitch. I can see you're dying to.
帮我阻止他们
Help me stop them.
不好意思  我对当英雄这种事不感兴趣
Sorry, I'm not interested in being a hero.
你这周恶棍当得却挺称职
Well, you're doing a pretty lousy job of being a villain this week.
圣诞快乐  巴里
Merry Christmas, Barry.
我刚才还在回想十年前
I was just thinking about a big drug bust
我和辛格开展的那次大规模的缉毒行动
that me and Singh made about ten years ago.
行动结束后  我们午餐去吃了牛排
Afterward, we went for a steak lunch
以庆祝工作圆满完成
to treat ourselves for a job well done.
点菜的时候
And while we were ordering,
我的胸口就有点异样
I got this feeling in my chest.
感觉好像心缩成了一团
Like my heart was being squeezed.
我就知道要出事了
I knew something wasn't right.
所以我就给你学校打电话
So I called your school
护士跟我说她刚好要打电话给我
and the nurse said to me that she was just about to call me.
爱瑞斯正被送往医院
Iris was on her way to the hospital.
那次她阑尾穿孔了
When her appendix burst.
我能意识到  心里能觉察到
And I knew it. I could feel it, right here.
我知道我的孩子需要我
I knew my kid needed me.
那么如果说当父母的都能感觉到
So if I have that feeling as a parent,
为什么我对自己的儿子就没这种感觉
why didn't I feel it from my son?
乔  你不知道他的存在过错不在你
Joe, it's not your fault that you didn't know about him.
不  是我的错
Yeah, it was.
弗朗辛跑出戒毒所那次
When Francine left rehab that last time,
我本该去找她
I should've looked for her.
我是个警察  我本可以找到她的
I'm a cop. I could've found her.
把她带回来
Brought her back here.
再试一次  再努力一些
Tried again. Tried harder.
你那时是在保护爱瑞斯
You were protecting Iris.
20年以来我一直都这么告诉自己
I've been telling myself that for 20 years.
一个撒了20年的谎  我不是在保护她
A 20-year lie, but I wasn't protecting her,
我是在保护自己  我再也受不了了
I was protecting myself. I couldn't stand it anymore.
我再也
I couldn't--
我讨厌我自己不能帮弗朗辛
I hated not being able to help Francine.
所以说她死了对我来说更容易一些
So it was easier for her to be dead.
远离我的生活  远离我们的生活
Out of my life. Out of our lives.
但真的不是为了爱瑞斯
But it wasn't for Iris.
是我自私
I was being selfish.
却让那可怜的男孩付出了代价
And that poor boy paid the price.
乔...
Joe...
他生来就没有爸爸
He never had a father...
临睡前给他讲故事  教他怎么玩橄榄球
To read to him at night, show him to throw a football,
让他有安全感
to make him feel safe,
感受到爱
and loved.
谁能教他如何成为一个男子汉  巴里
Who taught him how to be a man, Barry?
"他"  我都不敢说出他的名字
"Him." I can't even say his name.
我都干了些什么
What have I done?
乔
Joe, look
你一直在我身边
you have been there for me
从我遇到你后的每一天都如此
Every day since I met you.
你一直都在
You have.
如果你有机会的话  你也会
You would have done the exact same thing for him
对他做同样的事情  我知道的
if you could have, I know it.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你的搭档去哪里了  斯皮沃特
Where's your partner, Spivot?
我怎么知道  我又不是他的保姆
I don't know, I'm not his babysitter.
对不起  上司  我不知道乔去哪里了
I'm sorry, sir. I'm not sure where Joe is.
? 红鼻子的极速者小闪电 ?
? flash-y the red-nosed speedster ?
? 穿着闪亮亮的服装 ?
? Had a very shiny suit ?
? 如果你曾见过他 ?
? And if you ever saw him ?
? 你可能会吐出来 ?
? You might even want to puke ?
圣诞快乐  小伙伴们  我又回来了
Merry christmas, kiddie-winks. I'm back!
立刻把技术援助反应部队叫来
Get TARU down here now.
我要知道他是怎么做到的
I want to know how he's doing this.
市民们  假期可以是
Citizens, you know, the holidays can be a time
回顾往年的日子
for gentle reflection on the year past.
我们的大起大落
Our ups and downs,
我们的胜利与心碎
Our triumphs and heartaches,
但是别忘了  它同时也可以是
But don't forget, it can also be a time
给我们敌人开膛破肚的日子
for disemboweling our enemies.
在地球二上没有魔术师
We don't have a trickster on earth-2.
他是很特殊的
He's one of a kind.
填充我长袜的将会是
My stocking won't be completely stuffed
闪电侠血淋淋的残肢
until it's filled to the brim with bloody flash parts.
你要怎么做呢  极速怪人
So what do you say, speed freak?
想来陪我玩玩吗
Want to roast chestnuts?
我要所有的战略部队都提升到最高警惕
I want all tactical units on high alert.
跟其他区域联系好
Get in touch with other precincts,
我要看到指挥官们在做协调部署
I want watch commanders coordinating deployment.
斯皮沃特  你要去...
Spivot, I need you to...
斯皮沃特
Spivot!
视频中有他所在地点的线索吗
Are there any clues as to where he is based on the video?
我找不到
None that I can see.
大家快来看  他的眼角膜中
Guys, there's a reflection
有个什么东西的映射  看到了吗
of something in his cornea, see?
-那是什么  -不大清楚
- What is that? - Not sure.
那是摇摇熊先生
That's Mr. Jiggle Wiggle.
-什么  -那是个玩具
- Come again? - It's a doll.
小朋友玩的公仔玩具
A stuffed children's toy.
在我女儿六岁的时候我给她买了一个
I gave one to my daughter when she was six.
摇摇熊先生是由冈村玩具公司制造的
Mr. Jiggle Wiggle was manufactured by Okamura Toys...
冈村玩具公司
找到了
Yahtzee!
冈村玩具公司曾在中城拥有一个装货厂
Okamura once had a shipping facility in central city
但是四年前关闭了
that shut down four years ago;
从那之后就无人使用
it's been abandoned ever since.
天气巫师在那里怎么办  天气魔棒还没玩完呢
What if weather wizard's there? The wand's not finished.
魔术师就要玩完了
The trickster is.
你在这里做什么
What are you doing here?
跟你一样  想要抓凶手
Same thing as you. Trying to catch a murderer.
我们可不能让圣诞节占头彩
We can't let Christmas hog all the holiday fun!
犹太光明节快乐
Happy Hanukkah!
我们绝对是在目睹
I'm afraid we are definitely looking at
一场盖棺定论的葬礼
closed casket funerals.
我们没地方跑
There's nowhere for me to run us to!
那我们该怎么办
So what should we do?
抓紧我
Hold me.
-我正在跟其他人约会呢  -我也是  别放手
- I'm seeing someone. - Me too. Don't let go.
警探
Detective.
这只是个抓你的圈套
It was all just a trap for you.
马登和杰西根本不在
Mardon and Jesse aren't even here.
他们还不知道在哪里
They're still on the loose.
你是怎么知道要来这里的
How did you know to come here?
因为视频里有映射
Because there was a reflection
在杰西眼中映射出的摇摇熊先生
in Jesse's eye of Mr. Jiggle Wiggle.
而且那就是我爸爸...
And that's the thing that my dad...
现在说这些都没用了
It doesn't even matter.
所以你就甩下后援自己一个人过来这里
That's why you came here alone without any backup?
因为你父亲
Because of your father?
你对我一无所知
You don't know anything about me.
我知道你很大意
I know that you're being reckless.
而且我相信你生命中重要的人
And I'm sure the people in your life
都很在乎你  不希望看到你受伤
care enough about you to not want to see you get hurt.
可是马登没有杀我父亲
Except Mardon didn't kill my father.
都是我
I did.
他开着一家小鞋铺
See, he had a little shoe shop,
我们都没什么钱
and we didn't have any money,
所以我放学后要去帮忙
So I worked there after school.
可是有一天我不想去了
Except one day I decided not to show up,
因为我愚蠢地想要跟朋友们在一起
Because I was being stupid and silly with my friends.
我甚至没有打电话告诉他我逃课了
I didn't even call to tell him that I was ditching.
所以他就带着储蓄去了银行
So he brought the deposits to the bank,
而不是我去的
Not me.
所以他就被马登枪杀了  而不是我被杀
He was shot and killed by Mardon, not me.
所以你就成为了一个警察
That's why you became a cop.
参加超能力者特别行动小组
Joined the meta-human task force.
这样我杀马登时就会是合法的
It'll be legal when I kill Mardon.
我的这上半辈子
I have made my whole life
都在为我父亲取回公道而奔波
about getting justice for my father,
即使我没有自己的生活
Even if it meant I didn't have a life
而现在我遇到了一个很好的人
And now I met a really great guy,
我甚至觉得这一切都不是真的
And that doesn't even feel real to me
我很害怕他会发现我有多生气
And I'm scared he's gonna find out how angry I am.
我都不知道我为什么要告诉你这些
I don't even know why I'm telling you this.
有时对蒙面的人吐露心声
Sometimes it's just easier to say things
要更容易一些
to someone with no face.
谢谢你救了我
Thank you for saving me.
就算你抓到了这个让你遭受不幸的人
You know, even if you get this guy that wronged you,
也不见得你接下来的人生会好过
it doesn't always make things better.
总比现在要好
It has to be better than this.
帕蒂  还是我
Patty, it's me. Again.
我很想和你谈谈  我很担心你
I'd really love to talk. I'm worried about you.
总之  等你有空
Anyway, just give me a call
记得回个电话  好吗
when you get a chance, all right?
谢谢了  拜
Thank you. Bye.
-巴里  -什么事
- Barry. - Yeah?
怎么样
How's it look?
太像了
Eerily familiar.
帕蒂怎么样了
How's Patty?
她...
She is, um,
一直在用笑容掩饰她的痛处
hiding a lot of pain behind her smile.
人们都说情侣间相处久了
They say couples start to resemble each other
就变得很像对方了
after a little while.
问题是她对闪电侠敞开心扉  不是我
The thing is, I mean, she only opened up to Flash, not me.
所以就算跟她通上话了
So even if I could got her on the phone,
我也不知道该说什么
I don't know what to say.
就个人经验来说
Well, it's been my experience
陪伴就是最好的帮助
that just being around you can be a big help.
谢谢
Thank you.
我想要苹果手机  平板电脑和音乐播放器
I want an iPhone, an iPad, and an iTouch.
悠着点  贪心鬼
Dial it back, Mr. Greedy.
这些可在圣诞老人能力范围之外哦
Those are a little out of Santa's price range.
这个怎么样
How about this?
记住了  明天才可以打开
Now remember, don't open it until tomorrow.
这可是惊喜哦
It's a surprise.
你决定了吗
Have you decided?
我还需要时间
I need more time.
谁不是呢  现在就决定
Don't we all. Decide.
我需要时间
I need more time.
是要我去杀几个
Maybe if I go up there
你的新朋友
and kill a few of your new friends...
-不  -再给你一天时间
- No! - One more day.
我会向你女儿转告你的问候
I'll tell your daughter you said, "Hello."
那是什么  是马登吗
What's that? Is that Mardon?
肯定是他
That's definitely him.
大气压刚下降了200百帕
Atmospheric pressure just dropped 200 hectopascals.
-在哪里  -中城广场
- Where? - Central City Square.
圣诞树亮灯仪式
The tree lighting ceremony.
那可有成千上万人啊
There's thousands of people there.
很高兴见到你
Oh, glad to see you.
也许你能帮我
Maybe you can help me.
把你送回牢房吗
Help get back in to a jail cell?
-那我倒挺乐意  马克  -不
- It'll be my pleasure, Mark. - No.
听着  我正在想
No, see, I'm trying to decide
是用致命冰雹风暴
if I should kill everybody down there
还是更高级的酸雨  把下面的人
with a deadly hail storm, or--little trickier,
全杀死  你觉得呢
with acid rain, what do you think?
让我想想
Ah, let me think, um...
两个都不可以呢
how about neither?
你看见这个魔棒了吗  猜猜看
You see this wand here? Guess what?
各位  他会飞诶
Guys? He's flying.
他怎么会飞呢  什么时候的事啊
He can fly? Since when can he fly?
他用自己的超能力改变了周围的气压
Well, he's using his powers to alter the air pressure
制造了一团上升气流  可以
around him to create pockets of updraft that can--
不  他会飞
No, he can fly.
巴里  抓住他
Barry, get him.
你不会真以为我会
You didn't really think I'd let you hurt
让你伤害这些人吧
all these people, did you?
当然不
No, of course not,
但我猜你是想让我伤害你
but bet you're gonna let me hurt you.
圣诞快乐啊
Feliz navidad!
是时候开始真正的圣诞大战了
Time for a real war on Christmas.
这是什么
What is this?
装着炸弹的盒子
That is a box with a bomb in it.
没错  我今天已经送出了100个盒子
Yup, I've handed out about 100 of them today.
赠予的感觉真好啊
It feels so good to give.
现在有100个随机的孩子
You see, right now, there are 100 random children
每人都带回家一个
who've each taken home a box
跟这个一样的盒子
just like that one
放在他们的圣诞树下
and are shoving it under their Christmas tree.
你根本不可能找回所有盒子
There's no way for you to get all of them,
就算你知道去哪儿找也不行
even if you knew where to look.
别  别这样
Oh, no, please don't do this.
什么  我吗  毁掉100个家庭
What? Me? Kill 100 families?
不  那取决于你
No, that's up to you.
取了你的性命我就很开心了
I'm happy just to take your life.
所以情况就是这样
So this is how it's gonna be.
你站在这儿  让我终结了你
You are gonna stand there and let me end you.
当着所有人的面
Very publicly
痛苦不堪
and very painfully
然后我就放过所有人
and I'll let everybody live,
但是如果我看到
but if I see even
你身上哪怕有一丝电光
a little flicker of electricity on you...
那城里所有的棺材商
the casket makers in this town
得度过一个非常愉快的圣诞节了
are gonna have a very merry Christmas.
那么  闪电侠
So, Flash...
你的决定是什么
What's it gonna be?
这就对了嘛
There you go.
他们要杀了巴里
They're gonna kill Barry!
除非我们找到那些炸弹
Unless we find those bombs.
-西斯科  -杰伊  不可能
- Cisco? - Jay, there's no way.
有办法
There is a way.
找到100枚随机散布的炸弹吗
To find 100 randomly-placed bombs?
我们没必要找到一百个
We don't have to find 100.
只要找到一个  就能搞定全部的炸弹
We just have to find one. And then we get rid of them all.
-怎么做  -利用缺口
- How? - A breach.
没错  我们送走了古鲁德
That's right. We sent Grodd away.
可以用同样的方法把炸弹送走
We can do the same to these bombs, all of them.
你的工作室有无人机吗
Do you have a drone in your workshop?
-有  -能飞吗
- Yeah. - Does it fly?
-能  -那就好
- Yeah. - Good.
我要拿走  不还了
I'm taking it. You're not getting it back.
我去把车启动
I'll warm up the van.
我正在交叉比对用信用卡付过过路费
I'm cross-referencing credit card statements with
和家庭账单  并且有十岁以下小孩的家庭
toll road usage and families with children under ten.
位置
等等
Hold up...
调头  就在后面两条街
make a U-turn. Two streets back.
把你的玩具交给我
Your toys. Give them to me.
妈妈
Mom!
闪电侠  你没事吧
Flash, you all right?
脸色不太好啊
You don't look so good.
我知道
I know...
我会给你一击
I'll give you a jolt.
哈里  你有什么计划
Harry, what is the plan?
奇点附近52个缺口的其中一个
One of the 52 breaches opened by the singularity
就在城市正上方22公里处
is 1/4 mile directly above the city.
我们要利用你的无人机
We are gonna use your drone
把炸弹放进缺口里
to put this bomb into that breach.
要怎么做  炸了一个  还有99个会炸呢
Okay, how does that work? One down, 99 to blow.
基础物理  拉蒙  磁性
Basic physics, Ramon. Magnetism.
磁性  磁铁异性相吸
Magnetism. Magnets of opposite poles attract one another.
帮帮我  加里克
Help me out, Garrick.
如果我们能改变这个炸弹的维频
If we can change the dimensional frequency of this bomb
再把炸弹放进缺口里
and get it through that breach--
它会把其余的炸弹一起吸引进去
It'll drag all the rest of the bombs right along with it.
我来操控  好  准备好了
I'll drive. Okay, hold on.
我玩够了
I'm done.
他就交给你了
He's all yours.
天呐
Oh, God...
想像一下这座城市如此爱戴你
To think this city worships you!
但是等我杀了闪电侠
But, when I kill the Flash,
人们就会意识到我才是拯救中城的人
they'll realize I'm the man who saved Central City!
成功了
It's working.
-是你干的吗  -不是  干掉他
- Was that you? - No! Gut him!
好了  马上就干掉他了
All right, I'm gutting already.
巴里  炸弹消失了
Barry, the bombs are gone.
喜欢磁铁吗  贱人
How do you like the magnets, bitch?
警探  炸弹搞定了  不会有人因此再受伤
Detective, it's taken care of. They can't hurt anyone else.
你要做什么
What are you doing?
-你要做什么  -为了我父亲
- What are you doing? - This is for my father.
不不不  警探
No, no, no, Detective!
警探  不  不能开枪
Detective, no. You can't do this.
他为了几百块杀了我父亲
He killed my father for a couple hundred dollars.
到底是什么这么重要  要我父亲丧命
What was so important that my father had to lose his life?
马登会受到应有的惩罚的
Mardon will get what he deserves.
他应得的惩罚就是死
He deserves to die!
不是以这种方式
Not like this!
你没那个胆量  美女
You don't have it in you, pretty lady.
过去四年我一直在问自己
I've been asking myself that for the last four years,
现在我知道了
and now I know.
别开枪  帕蒂
No, Patty!
扣下扳机  你的人生也就结束了
You pull that trigger, your life ends too.
你会坐牢
You will go to prison.
你生命中的一切人事
Everything and everyone that you could have had in your life
都会再次从你身边被夺走
will be taken from you. Again.
不让马登得逞  他就抢不走你身边的事物
Mardon can't take anything else from you unless you let him.
我不认识你父亲
I didn't know your father,
但我知道他不希望你这样
but I know he wouldn't want this.
不希望你记住仇恨
Not over him.
放下枪
Please. Please.
马克·马登  你被逮捕了
Mark Mardon, you're under arrest.
说得太动听了
That was beautiful.
巴里
Barry, hey.
大家都要去我们家过圣诞节
Everyone's heading over to our place for Christmas.
你没事吧
You okay?
没事  没有什么是超能力者的
Yeah, no, nothing a little meta-human
再生能力无法治愈的
regenerative healing capabilities won't cure.
弗朗辛谈得怎么样
How'd it go with Francine?
还行  其实还不错
It was good. It was really good, actually.
这么久以来我一直谎称她过世了
I mean, I spent so long lying about her being dead
以致我自己都开始相信这点
that I started to believe it myself.
可事实上  这些情感一直存在
But the truth is, those feelings were always there.
那种愤怒  悔恨  内疚
That anger, that regret, the guilt...
我只是没想过我需要原谅她
I just didn't realize how much I needed to forgive her.
而现在
And now...
还有一个房间给小韦斯特
there's room for another West.
你见到他了吗
Did you meet him?
不  他还不知道
No. He still doesn't know.
我们会见面的
That'll come.
-你有个儿子  -我知道
- You have a son. - I know, right?
太疯狂了
It's crazy.
说到这个  拿着
Speaking of which, take this.
什么
What?
不不不  我不能拿
No, no, no, no, I can't take that.
我一直说有一天  我会把这个给我儿子
I've always said that one day i would give this to my son...
而我现在有儿子了
and now I have.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
圣诞快乐  谢谢
Merry Christmas. Thank you.
我爱你
Love you.
-我也爱你  -回家见
- I love you too. - See you at the house.
我知道你不是他
I know that you're not him...
他不在这里  我还是要说
But he's not here and I have to say this for me.
在视频留言里
In that video message,
你说
you said that--
我不会真正的快乐
that I would never really be happy...
我不断努力  非常努力
and I've been trying-- I've been trying really hard.
听了乔的一番话
After what Joe said,
还有帮助帕蒂
and helping Patty,
我发现我心里还是有你
I realize that you're still in my heart.
虽然我很恨
How much I hate you
你的所作所为
for what you've done.
我不想再恨你  我不能
I don't want to hate you anymore, I can't.
我不能再恨你
Can't hate you anymore.
我原谅你
I forgive you.
你要我帮忙吗
You need me for something?
不用了  我没事
No, no, I'm good.
今晚来我家过圣诞吧
You know, you should come over for Christmas tonight.
你不该一个人待着
you shouldn't be alone.
很好的提议
It's a nice offer.
我要跟女儿一起庆祝
I can't celebrate without my daughter.
好吧
All right.
够烈吗
Strong enough?
喝了就知道
We'll see.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
你拿着什么
What do you have there?
-槲寄生  -什么是槲寄生
- Mistletoe. - What's mistletoe?
是一种半寄生植物
Oh, um, it's a hemiparasitic plant
从属于檀香科
from the genus santalaceae family
生长在北美洲
in North America, I think.
凯特琳  逗你玩的  地球二也有槲寄生
Caitlin, I'm kidding. We have mistletoe on earth-2.
没错  当然有
Right, of course.
而且我们还有这个传统
Um, we also have this tradition over there.
我们也有这个传统
We have that tradition here too.
终于啊
Finally.
我来开
Oh, let me get that.
-喝蛋酒吧  -好啊
- Eggnog, please? - Yeah.
很高兴你能来
Hi, I'm so glad you could make it.
谢谢你们邀请我
Aw, thank you for having me.
圣诞快乐  这是给你的
Merry Christmas. This is for you.
-谢谢  -不客气
- Thank you. - Of course.
我好担心你
I've been really worried about you.
-一直打给你  -我知道
-I've been calling. - I know...
我真的很抱歉
And I'm really sorry.
我在忙一些事
I just have been dealing with something by myself,
我要告诉你是什么事
but I want to tell you about it.
我准备好告诉你了
I think that I'm ready to.
有人提醒了我这很重要
Someone reminded me of what's important,
只要你想知道  我就跟你分享
so if you want to hear, I would like to share it with you.
这会是我收到的最好礼物
That would be the best gift I could get.
这是我给你买的甜蜜毛衣
I don't know. This is a really sweet sweater.
希望这俩都很甜蜜
I hope it's as sweet as this one.
挺相称的
It's matching.
-谢谢  -不客气
- Thank you. - Of course.
-斯皮沃特警探  -你好
- Detective spivot. - Hi.
-你怎么来了  -圣诞快乐
- What brings you here? - Merry Christmas.
我是巴里的女友
Well, uh, I'm... Barry's girlfriend.
-该公开了  -干杯
- About time. - Cheers.
还有人没到吗
Are we expecting anybody else?
-据我所知没有  -也许哈里改变心意了
- Not that I know of. - Maybe Harry changed his mind.
你好  我是沃利  弗朗辛的儿子
Hi, I'm Wally. I'm Francine's son.
我...我...我是乔
I'm--I'm--I'm Joe.
这是爱瑞丝
This is iris.
我只是想...
Uh, I just wanted to--
我不知道
I don't know.
我来得不是时候  你们有客人
I guess now's a bad time. You've got company, so...
不不不不  进来吧
No. No, no, no. Come in.
时间到了  威尔斯
Time's up, Wells.
你决定好了吗
What's it gonna be?
我知道你在干什么
I know what you're doing.
我知道你为什么不断从我们的地球
I know why you keep sending villain after villain
送恶人过来
from our earth to this one.
你要巴里变得更快
You want Barry to get faster.
你要他变得更强
You want him to get stronger.
你要他变得更有能量  拥有更多的
You want him to become more powerful, more full of...
神速力
speed force.
你把他当圣诞鹅养肥
You're fattening him up like a Christmas goose.
他有越多能量
The more power he has,
我就能取走越多
the more I can take
你会帮我的
and you're going to help me.
我要见她
Let me see her first.
爸爸
Daddy?
你还好吗  他有伤害你吗
Are you okay? Did he hurt you?
快救我
Please help me.
不要让他把我关回去
Don't let him take me back there.
我不会
I won't--
现在决定吧
Now decide.
以换回你女儿的性命
In return for your daughter's life.
我帮你
I'll do it.
我会帮你偷闪电侠的速度
I'll help you to steal The Flash's speed.